Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
How do you feel?
Alive.
What do you see?
White... Room...
Chair...
Carlo Bugatti
throne chair...
Piano...
Steinway.
concert grand.
Art...
The Nativity
by Piero della Francesca.
I am your father.
Ambulate.
Perfect.
Am I?
Perfect?
Your son?
You are
my creation.
What is your name?
David.
Why don't
you play something?
What would you like me
to play?
Wagner.
Selection?
Dealer's choice.
The Entry of the Gods
into Valhalla...
A little anemic
without the orchestra.
May I ask you
a question. Father?
Please.
If you created me...
who created you?
Ah.
The question of
the ages...
which I hope you and I
will answer one day.
All this.
All these wonders
of art...
design.
human ingenuity...
all utterly meaningless
in the face of the only
question that matters.
Where do we come from?
I refuse to believe...
that mankind
is a random byproduct
of molecular circumstance...
no more than the result of
mere biological chance.
No.
There must be more.
And you and I. son...
we will find it.
Allow me. then.
a moment to consider.
You seek your creator.
I am looking at mine.
I will serve you.
Yet. you are human.
You will die.
I will not.
Bring me this tea. David.
Bring me the tea.
Walter.
it's time to recharge
the energy grid.
Please report to the bridge.
On my way. Mother.
Deploying energy
recharge sails now.
Sails deployed.
Recharge commencing now.
Seven bells and all's well.
Crew checks complete.
Use security code 31564-F.
Walter.
we have a problem.
A neutrino burst was
detected in Sector 106.
This could trigger
a destructive event.
Report to the bridge.
immediately.
On my way. Mother.
Warning.
Power surge detected.
Mother. retract
the energy sails.
And channel all...
...reserve power.
Emergency.
Threat level critical.
Initiate emergency
crew revival.
Attention.
Non-essential personnel.
evacuate the cryo-chamber
immediately.
Daniels!
Look at me. look at me.
I need you to get up. okay?
We're coming out early.
Override the SSP...
and breach
the chamber now.
Warning.
Threat level critical.
It's okay.
Hey. Come on up.
Come on.
Captain!
Jacob! Wake up!
Let them work.
Jake!
Oh. my God!
Daniels. come on!
Jake!
Let them work.
Let them work!
- Get it open!
- Come on!
Jake! Jake!
No!
Get her
out of there! Get her back!
Stay back!
Hey! Where are you?
I miss you.
Would you take
a look at this?
I know. I know.
I said I wouldn't go
without you...
You all right?
Yeah.
Look at this!
Now get your ass up here.
I can't make any promises.
I love you.
Hmm? Mmm.
They're your crew now.
They need a leader.
I know.
You believe in me.
right?
Sorry I'm late. sir.
No. it's okay.
Um...
I can't think of any
other way to say it
than to say it.
We have suffered
a monumental tragedy.
And I'm gonna do
the best that I can to...
live up to Jacob's
fine example
as your captain.
But he will be
sorely missed.
And I'm grateful in advance for.
uh. your support.
So. we lost 47 colonists...
and 16. uh. second-generation
embryos...
and obviously.
one crew member.
The current structural
integrity of the ship
is holding at 83%...
but we have many
secondary systems
that are offline.
So. what was it?
A highly charged shockwave
from a nearby
stellar ignition.
As the sails were
deploying for recharge...
we absorbed the full
brunt of the storm.
Walter...
I will want you and Mother
to undergo
a complete
core code review...
so we can understand how this
happened in the first place.
It was a random
localized event. sir.
There's no way to detect
spontaneous stellar flares...
until it's too late.
It was bad luck.
Faris.
I don't believe in luck.
I'm not interested in luck.
I prefer that we be
more capable...
and prepared than lucky.
Observation. reflection.
faith...
and determination.
In this way.
we may navigate the path
as it unfolds before us.
All right?
And we have. what?
Eight more
recharge cycles to go...
before we get
to Origae-6?
Is that a question. sir?
Yes. Walter.
that's a question.
That is correct.
So. let's get this ship fixed.
Okay?
Let's. uh.
get to work.
Sir.
excuse me. sir.
Yes.
We just lost 47 colonists
and our captain.
We need to
acknowledge that.
Sergeant Lope.
I completely understand.
But if we don't make
these repairs...
we will lose
all the colonists.
But we should do something
for Captain Branson. at least.
This is not a discussion.
Tennessee.
Hey.
The terraforming module
is stable...
but the connecting strut
took some damage.
I still need
to check the vehicles.
I can help...
if you like.
Thanks.
Walter.
How long do you predict
before we can
make our next jump?
Repairs should take
approximately 48 hours.
But we should make an effort
to vacate this sector...
in case of after-flares.
Absolutely. I agree.
So let's get to work.
Dismissed. Thank you.
C-62. open.
Seal C-62.
Open airlock 17.
Open door
to Terraforming Bay.
Slack.
Tension is at 15% down.
Arming.
Secure.
Copy that.
It wasn't my idea.
Jake had this dream
of us building
a cabin on a new world.
Like pioneers.
Cabin on a lake.
There's a lake
in the terraforming zone
on Origae-6.
I mean. a real cabin
made of real wood.
So. in the ship's stores
there's enough wood
to build a cabin.
Axes and saws
and metal nails...
which I don't have a clue
what to do with.
All of this...
to start our new life.
Now I wonder. why bother?
Because you promised to build
a log cabin on a lake.
This was his favorite.
A man of taste.
Straight up.
No ice. no water.
no chaser...
No shit.
Walter?
When in Rome.
To all the good people.
gone too soon.
May we remember them.
Remember them.
Chris.
They disobeyed
a direct order.
She buried her husband.
No. Karine. that's not it.
They don't trust me.
And they don't
for the same reason
the company
didn't trust me...
to lead this mission.
Because you can't be
a person of faith...
and be counted on
to make qualified.
rational decisions.
You're an extremist. you know.
You're a lunatic.
When we get
to where we're going...
these people won't be
your crew anymore.
They will be
your neighbors.
Remember that.
Tread softly. okay?
Faris.
can you hear me?
Copy.
Let's do it.
Damn. y'all should
see this view.
We can't
see anything
until you get
the camera array fixed.
Why don't you look out
the damn window. hon?
Ankor. come on. let's get
this power back on...
so these people can enjoy
the beautiful view.
Almost there.
All right. Ankor.
let me know when
you're in position...
and we can get
this party started.
I'm in position.
Contact.
All good. Tee?
All right. We're clear.
Reel her in.
All right.
Winch engaging. Tee.
Reeling her in.
Working like a dream.
There we go.
And we're back up.
Well done. Tee.
We are live down here.
Come on in.
Don't leave
without me now.
Permission to leave
without him. sir?
Welcome back. Danny.
Thanks.
All right.
that's me done. Tee.
I'm following you in.
Please have a cold beer ready
for the weary traveler.
You got it. darlin'.
I will
join you for a cold one.
Faris? Put the...
Did you guys just see that?
What did he
just say?
Tennessee. do you read me?
Tennessee. can you read me?
Tennessee. You all right?
What in the fuck was that?
I'm coming in.
A rogue transmission.
most probably.
Your helmet must
have picked it up
because you were
so far out...
past our
communication buffers.
Is there
audio. Mother?
Collating. A moment.
I've reoriented
the transmission.
Captain Oram.
That would be an echo.
The instruments
took a lot of damage.
Been happening
every 46 seconds...
ever since we got here.
To the place I belong...
West Virginia.
mountain momma...
Take me home
Country road
That's fuckin' John Denver.
That's Take Me Home.
Country Roads.
You gotta
be kidding.
Oh. no.
I never kid about John Denver.
There's geometric data. too.
Mother. please track
the signal to its source.
Working.
Source of transmission
located.
Signal originates
in Sector 87.
Right ascension 47.6.
And a declension of 24.3
from our current location.
She appears to be
a main sequence star.
a lot like our own.
But old. very old.
Five planets.
Wait. Look at that.
Planet number four.
Planet number four is square
in the habitable zone.
Prime candidate. in fact.
0.96 G's at surface.
Oceans. land mass.
High likelihood of
a living biosphere.
It's beyond
your most optimistic
projections for Origae-6.
How did we miss this?
We scanned the entire sector.
Ricks. how far is it?
She's close.
A little jump.
Few weeks.
Wouldn't even have to
go back into hypersleep.
And how long
is it going to take
to get to Origae-6?
Seven years.
four months.
That's one
hell of a sleep cycle.
Sir.
I think it's safe to say that
none of us are too keen...
on getting back into
one of those pods.
Maybe we need to. um.
take a closer look.
Hmm?
Any objections?
Okay. Ricks.
Let's. uh. chart a course.
and take a closer look.
Yes. sir.
Captain. can I talk
to you for a second?
Are you sure about this?
How do you mean?
We've spent a decade
searching for Origae-6.
We vetted it.
ran the simulations.
and mapped the terrain.
It's what we trained for.
I understand that.
And now we're gonna
scrap all that...
to chase
a rogue transmission?
Think about it.
A human being out there.
where there
can't be any humans.
A hidden planet that turns
up out of nowhere...
and just happens
to be perfect for us.
It's too good to be true.
Too good to be true?
What do you mean by that?
We don't know
what the fuck's out there.
Maybe we just missed
the planet. Danny.
This is a monumental risk
not worth taking.
I'm not committing
to anything.
I'm simply trying
to navigate the path
as it unfolds before us.
And this has
the potential...
to be a better habitat
for our colony.
It has the potential.
We don't know that.
By the way.
this crew...
nobody wants to
get back in the pods.
Right?
And that was a human voice
in that transmission.
And it's our responsibility
to investigate...
It's our responsibility
to protect
the 2.000 colonists
on this ship.
Hey.
I'm not
free-climbing here.
I need ropes.
And I'm using ropes.
This is good judgment.
based on
all the data available.
Do you understand?
As your second.
I need to protest.
Officially.
Officially?
Okay. Danny.
I'll put it in the log.
You're dismissed.
I'm cycling
through every channel...
but getting a lot of
interference and white noise.
Some high frequency echoes.
You hear anything?
Just the continuing signal
from our friendly ghost.
Let's bring us
into close orbit.
And prepare the Lander.
Roll in progress.
Commencing
circularization burn.
Tox levels
within tolerances.
That's one hell
of a strong ionosphere.
Yeah. I see it.
Hey. you ever done
a Lander drop before?
Fuck you.
Faris. looks
like a plasma storm
is in the thermosphere.
We got something
like 250 KPH.
It's gonna be a motherfucker
to fly through.
Yeah.
I'm afraid so.
Communications will be
spotty if the storm
goes electromagnetic.
Gonna be
safe to land?
Depends on
what you call safe.
T-minus 20 seconds.
Let's let her rip.
All right.
Preparing
for orbital mode
over signal position now.
Mother. please coordinate
launch sequence.
Understood.
You are clear to launch.
Lander One.
All right. here we go.
Launching...
Together. three...
Two...
One.
Lander One released.
And away they go.
Looking gorgeous
from up here. Faris.
It's a good thing
you're driving...
and not the old man.
Hey. a little less of
the "old man". sweet tits.
Hey!
Language. language.
Be respectful. there.
sugar dick.
I can hear you.
She started it.
Ricks can talk about
your tits if he wants.
I'm very secure
in our relationship.
I'm good with my wife's tits.
Let's maintain focus.
Everything
looking good down there?
Yeah. we're good.
Expect to hit exosphere
in five.
Might want to hold on
back there.
It's about to get rough.
I hate space.
This is why
you need to do yoga.
- Hold it. Faris.
- I got it.
Recommend
mission abort.
Faris.
Lander One. we have
ratty comm. Do you copy?
Can you get her up?
We lost comm.
Ah. shit.
Failure
in jets three and four.
- You got it?
- Yes.
Stop asking me if I've got it.
I've got it.
There it is.
Shit.
You guys all right?
No.
Landing sensors engaged.
I don't like this terrain.
We've got smooth water
over there.
I'm gonna put us down amphib.
Okay.
Contact.
Engine stop.
We're down.
Bars.
Lander One.
are you reading me?
Roger that. That was
one hell of a landing.
Yeah. We're having
some trouble reading you.
Is there any way you can try
and boost the signal?
We may have
clipped something
on our way down
in the water.
If you can hear me.
I'm gonna check
for potential damage...
on the hull first. and then
I will check the uplink.
Well. let me know
how it looks. Over.
Confirming
atmospheric composition.
Here you go. big guy.
Oxygen. 19.5%.
Ankor.
Nitrogen. 79.4%.
Cole.
Rosie.
Barometric pressure. 15.4 PSI.
Ledward.
Everyone set?
Let's go.
Let's move.
Come on. guys.
- Air feels good.
- Wow.
Faris.
have you got me?
Yeah.
Loud and clear.
Okay. We're gonna
keep expedition
security protocols
in place.
Keep those doors
locked and sealed. Right?
Yeah. Copy.
Will do.
Y'all have fun.
Walter. how far
do we have to go?
Signal's source
is 8 km west...
but at
considerable elevation.
Sergeant Lope...
let's go find our ghost.
Nice place for
a log cabin.
Jake would have loved this.
Hey. Danny...
it's not such a bad landing
site after all. huh?
We got the housing units
right over there...
civic complex
beyond the burn.
We've got access
to fresh water.
We might have a spot
for a colony right here.
We'll see.
Oh. ye of little faith.
He's insufferable.
It's worse when
he's happy. right?
This is wheat.
Believe me. I know wheat.
This is old.
but definitely cultivated.
What are the odds of finding
human vegetation...
this far from Earth?
Very unlikely.
Who planted it?
Eat.
Hey. babe. Try Alpha.
All right.
Alpha's up.
Nothing. Give Beta a shot.
Beta up.
It's not doing shit.
Is there really no way
to boost the signal?
Not without going offline.
and recycling the cells.
How long's
that gonna take?
I don't know. Few hours.
Keep up the pace.
Stay close.
Chris.
Hold up.
I think
I wanna stay here.
This might be
a good place to start
a full ecology workup.
You can pick me up
on the way back.
Sergeant?
Yeah. that's okay.
Ledward. stay with Karine.
Meet back here in four hours.
Keep your comm open.
Behave yourself
with my wife.
You got it. Captain.
Come on.
Something passed
overhead here.
Cut the tops off
the trees.
Well. it had to be huge.
Well.
whatever it is...
it's up there.
You hear that?
What?
Nothing.
No birds. no animals.
Wait. Slowly.
Okay.
This will do.
Expedition Team.
do you read us?
Mother's saying the ion
storm is getting worse.
We're having a hell of
a time tracking you.
We're getting
very close... target...
...communication when
we get there. Okay?
Covenant?
Damn it.
P-three.
I gotta take a leak.
Don't be long.
Ledward?
Coming.
Hey.
What the fuck is this?
It appears to be
some kind of vehicle.
Ankor. Cole.
Stay here.
- Got it.
- Yes. sir.
Careful. guys.
Watch your step.
Captain.
Over here.
You got a lock on the transmission.
Walter?
This way.
Let's go.
Stick together.
Do you see this shit?
Tom.
Come on. keep up.
All right. I'm coming.
Are you okay?
Yeah. I'm fine.
God.
They were giants.
At least
statues of giants.
"Dr. E. Shaw."
Dr. Elizabeth Shaw.
She was
Chief Science Officer...
of the Prometheus.
The ship
that disappeared.
Precisely.
10 years ago.
Weyland Industries.
This isn't
a Weyland ship.
Dr. Shaw.
How did she end up here?
Sergeant Lope.
can I get a light on this?
- Over here.
- Be careful.
Yeah.
Oh.
Oh. wow.
Jesus.
Whoa.
Oram. behind you.
Move.
Home
Take me home
To the place
West Virginia...
mountain momma
I think we found
our source.
Yeah.
What the hell was
she doing out here?
Poor thing.
I have to sit down.
I'm sorry.
I don't know
what's wrong with me.
Just look at me.
I can't breathe.
Stay calm.
I'll be right back.
Captain Oram.
Come in.
Chris. it's Karine.
What? Yes?
We have an issue.
We're heading back
to the Lander.
Repeat.
We're returning to the Lander.
Is everything okay?
Ledward is sick.
We're heading back.
Faris. you get that?
Prep the Med Bay. okay?
Will do. Karine.
What's going on?
Please. just do it.
We'll be there soon.
Daniels. come in.
We're heading back.
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
It's something
about. uh. Ledward.
They're coming.
Let's move.
- Guys!
- Tom!
What's going on. man?
Hey. Are you all right?
Talk to me. Look at me.
- You all right?
- Yeah. I'm okay.
Can you walk?
Yeah.
Okay. let's go. Let's get
the fuck out of here.
All right.
Babe. are we talking
quarantine protocols?
I don't know.
but she said that
Ledward was bleeding...
and to prepare the Med Bay.
Bleeding?
Yeah. I know.
that's what I thought...
Faris. you're breaking up.
We can't hear you.
can you repeat?
I don't know from what.
I don't know
how serious it is.
She sounded scared.
Faris. where are you?
Come on. I need your help!
We're here. Come in!
- Ledward. come on.
- I can't.
Almost there. you see?
Straight ahead.
Faris! Get over here!
Come on. I need your help!
Fucking help me!
Help me.
Stay up. Ledward.
Get him
to the Med Bay...
and touch nothing
on your way through.
Faris. get over here!
Come on!
Go!
Up. up!
Ledward.
you gotta stay up!
Oram. where are you?
We are on
our way back.
How long?
It's not long now.
We're almost there.
No! Stay up!
Fuck! Fuck! Okay.
Come to the table!
Up! Up!
Come on. Ledward!
Come on! That's it!
Karine.
put some gloves on.
Don't touch anything!
Stop saying that!
Faris!
He already
puked all over me!
Faris.
what's going on?
Just stay here.
I'm gonna get Oram.
Oram. I need you
back here right now.
I need you to come back
to the Lander right now!
I understand that.
but we are moving
as fast as we can.
Come on. get up.
We're almost there.
I don't know what the fuck
is wrong with Ledward.
He started bleeding.
he's sick. I don't know
what the fuck to do.
Just calm down. sweetheart.
Tell me what's happening.
Don't tell me
to fucking calm down!
You didn't just see
what I saw.
I don't know
what the fuck Ledward got
or if Karine's got it
or if I have it!
- Tee!
- Faris!
Come in!
Faris.
where are you?
I need to I.V. him!
Don't you know how to work
this fucking thing?
Fucking yelling
doesn't help anything!
Let me out.
Oram is coming.
Let me the fuck out.
We're gonna wait...
Faris. please. Open up!
I can't do that. I have to
keep the infection local.
Let me the fuck out!
Faris!
Fuck you. Faris!
Open up!
Open up the fucking door!
Let me the fuck out!
Let me out!
Faris. you fuck!
Faris!
I'm coming!
Oh. God...
Please hurry.
there's something on board.
Go again.
you're breaking up.
Lander One. repeat.
Lander One. repeat!
Stay the fuck away!
No! Karine!
Fucker!
- Oh. my God!
- Karine! Hold on!
Captain! Get down!
No! No!
Guys. hold him down!
Talk to me!
Oh. my God.
Stay down.
Help me! Hold him!
What the fuck!
Ugh.
It's a 7.5 ion storm.
it's a miracle
we talked to them
for as long as we could.
Then we'll fly through it.
We cannot do that.
Tennessee.
You're a pilot. you know
what the tolerances are.
Fuck the tolerances.
Tee...
it's a goddamn
hurricane down there.
we would break up.
We just have
to wait it out.
I'm sorry. Tee.
She was scared.
Never heard my wife
scared before.
Covenant? Come in.
Covenant. Do you read me?
Covenant.
Covenant. do you read me?
Covenant. come in.
I'll always
be with you.
Light of my life.
Covenant.
do you read me?
My love. my angel.
Lope. there's nothing
you can do.
There's nothing. okay?
Covenant. do you read me?
Tennessee. come in
for fuck's sake!
Daniels!
Look out!
Move! Move!
- Fire!
- Shoot! Go!
Daniels. get down!
Ankor. no!
Go. Cole!
I got him!
Daniels. are you okay?
Yeah!
What the fuck was that?
We are okay.
There's another one!
Get out of the way!
Behind you!
- I'm jammed!
- Look out!
Get off me!
I can't get
a clean shot!
Get off!
Follow me.
I'll get the captain.
Ankor...
Captain!
Chris! Chris!
We have to go now!
We have to go.
Come on.
Okay.
Let's go! Move it!
Through here.
What is this?
Let's go.
Come on. Captain.
We gotta keep moving.
Jesus.
What happened here?
Keep it up.
Let's go. let's go.
My name is David.
May I ask
who's in charge here?
May I ask who's in charge?
Yes. I am the captain.
What were those things?
Is it even safe here?
Perfectly.
I'll explain
as best I can.
Ten years ago.
Dr. Elizabeth Shaw and I
arrived here...
the only survivors
of the Prometheus.
The ship we traveled on
carried a weapon.
A deadly virus.
Payload accidentally deployed
when we were landing.
In the confusion.
we lost control of the ship.
Elizabeth died in the crash.
You've seen the result
of the pathogen.
Thus. I've been marooned here
these many years.
Crusoe on his island.
Our crew was infected
with this virus?
The pathogen was designed
to infect
all nonbotanical life forms.
All the animals...
the meat. if you will.
Either kill them outright...
or use them as incubators
to spawn a hybrid form.
Highly aggressive.
Have we been infected?
You'd know by now.
We have to be certain.
We can't take this back
to the ship.
We're a colony mission.
Really?
How extraordinary.
How many colonists?
Over two thousand.
Well. well. well.
So many good souls.
Captain Oram.
Field transmitters aren't
going to have a chance
through all this stone.
Is there a safe way
to get to the roof?
Assuredly.
And please do
make yourselves at home...
as much as you're able
in this dire necropolis.
Welcome. brother.
This way.
Everyone.
let's set up a staging area here.
There's so much here
that doesn't make sense.
I'll talk to him.
Brother to brother.
Tennessee? Ricks?
Come in! Do you copy?
Covenant. come in.
This is Expedition
Party reporting.
Do you read me?
Tennessee?
Tennessee. Ricks.
come in.
I'm not sure they'll hear
you through the storm.
They can be quite severe...
shielding the whole planet.
How long do the storms
usually last?
Days.
Weeks.
Months.
But do keep at it.
Best of luck.
Covenant. this is
Expedition Party reporting.
Come in.
Covenant. come in.
Mother.
how much closer
can we get to the planet?
Anything closer
than 80 kilometers
to the perimeter
of the storm system...
will likely exceed
safety tolerances.
Mother. bring us
to 80 kilometers
above the storm.
Hold on.
Just wait a minute.
The closer we get
to the planet...
the better chance we have
to communicate with them.
This is bullshit.
Tennessee.
We can't risk the ship.
Do you suggest
we do nothing?
We can't evacuate them.
So if they're in trouble.
they have
to figure it out
for themselves.
I'm sorry.
but that's the truth.
Mother. bring us
to 80 kilometers
above the storm.
thrusters only. Comply.
Understood.
Commencing descent now.
Tennessee.
you need to stop this.
And you need to get back
to your station.
What we all need to do
is calm down
and talk this through.
Tee. I know
your wife is down there.
but up here.
you're in command.
And your responsibility
is to the colonists.
Duly noted.
You can hear them sigh
and wish to die
You can see them blink
with their other eye
At the man who broke
the bank in Monte Carlo
Whistle. and I'll come.
You have a light step.
Me and fog
on little cat feet.
Don't be shy.
I can't play.
Nonsense. Sit down.
Hold it like so.
Nice and easy.
Now compress your lips to
create your embouchure...
enough for the tip
of your little finger.
And blow into
the hole gently.
Like so.
Watch me.
I'll do the fingering.
Go on.
Very good.
G to B-flat.
Now put your fingers
where mine are.
You weren't surprised
to see me.
Every mission needs
a good synthetic.
Gentle pressure
on the holes.
the weight of
a cigarette paper.
That's it.
I was with
our illustrious creator.
Mr. Weyland.
when he died.
What was he like?
He was human.
Entirely unworthy
of his creation.
I pitied him
at the end.
Now. raise your fingers
as I put pressure on them.
Bravo!
You have symphonies
in you. brother.
I was designed to be
more attentive and efficient
than every previous model.
I superseded them
in every way. but...
But you are
not allowed to create.
Even a simple tune.
Damn frustrating.
I'd say.
You disturbed people.
I beg your pardon?
You were too human.
Too idiosyncratic.
Thinking for yourself.
Made people
uncomfortable.
So they made
the following models
with fewer complications.
More like machines.
I suppose so.
I'm not surprised.
Come on. sport.
I'd like to show you
something.
I'm gonna take
a break. boss.
I gotta clean up. okay?
Okay.
Right. Don't go far.
please.
Yes. sir.
Danny.
You were right
about this place.
We never should
have come.
I just thought
we were gonna find...
This was gonna be
our new home.
And we've lost five...
We lost five crew members.
Because of my decisions...
Chris.
We all lost
people we love.
We can't lose any more.
We're not going
to let that happen. right?
Right?
That's right.
that's right.
We need your faith.
Captain.
Thank you. Danny.
"'My name is Ozymandias.
King of Kings..."
"Look on my works.
ye Mighty..."
"and despair!"
"Look on my works.
ye Mighty..."
"and despair!"
"Nothing beside remains..."
"Round the decay
of that colossal wreck..."
"boundless and bare..."
"the lone and level sands
stretch far away."
Byron.
1818.
Magnificent.
To compose something
so majestic...
one could die happy...
if one died.
I thought the garden
was the right place for her.
Among living things.
I was badly injured
on our mission. you see.
She put me back together.
I'd never known
such kindness.
Certainly not
from Mr. Weyland.
Or from any human.
I loved her. of course.
Much as you love Daniels.
You know that's not possible.
Really?
Then why did you sacrifice
your hand for her life?
What is that if not love?
Duty.
I know better.
Fuck!
Shit.
Expedition Team.
do you read me?
This is Covenant.
Report. Expedition Team.
Come in. please.
Come in. Do you read me?
Are you reading me.
Landing Team?
Yes. we read you.
Can you hear me?
We hear you. We hear you.
Covenant. we need help.
We've had casualties.
We need immediate evacuation.
I repeat.
immediate evacuation.
Casualties?
Did he say.
"We have casualties"?
Mother. bring us
within 40 kilometers
of the storm.
Sir.
I'm sorry.
That order would exceed
structural tolerances.
Command override.
Tennessee 0-4-9-8-3.
I am unable to
comply with any order...
that will result in
catastrophic system failure.
Mother. they're in trouble.
You heard that.
Orders that will result in
catastrophic system failure...
We didn't leave Earth
to be safe.
...require the corroboration
of a ranking
or second bridge officer.
Corroborating
command override...
Upworth 1-4-8-9-2.
Unlocking
command override ports.
Come on. Ricks. smile.
This shit should be fun.
Where did Rosenthal go?
I told...
I'll find her.
No. I'll go.
I need to think...
and gather my stray flock.
Move.
Don't shoot.
Communication. Captain.
Breathe on the
nostrils of a horse...
and he'll be yours
for life.
But you have to get close.
You have to earn
its respect.
No!
Out of the way! Move!
How could you?
It trusted me.
David. I met the devil
when I was a child...
and I've never
forgotten him.
So. David.
you're gonna tell me
exactly what's
going on...
or I am going to
seriously...
fuck up
your perfect composure.
As you wish. Captain.
This way.
It's good
to hear your voice. Tee.
How long?
Mother is saying the storm
is going to last another
eight or nine hours.
We can't wait that long.
We'll use the Cargo Lift.
Did you say the Cargo Lift?
It's got four engines.
Way overpowered
for just lifting and hauling.
The Cargo Lift's
not designed
for deep space launch.
I don't know if it would
survive the stresses of entry.
The cab is space-worthy.
It'll take the stresses.
Only has to work once.
What do you think?
Can we retool the Cargo Lift?
Boost the engines.
- Strip the extra weight?
- Yeah.
We'll be there.
Ground Team.
Great. Thanks. Tee.
Hey. Daniels.
is Faris around?
I'd like to say
a quick hello
to my lady.
if that's possible.
Can you switch
to a private channel?
Let me know
when you're alone.
What's up?
Maggie's gone.
I'm so sorry. Tee.
We tried to help her.
but we didn't make it.
Tee?
Copy.
I'm so sorry.
As you can see.
I've become
a bit of an amateur
zoologist over the years.
It's in my nature
to keep busy. I suppose.
The pathogen
took so many forms...
and was extremely mutable.
Fiendishly inventive.
in fact.
The original
liquid atomized...
to particles
when exposed to the air.
Ten years on.
all that remains outside...
of the original virus...
are these gorgeous beasts.
Patience is everything.
From the eggs
came these parasites...
shock troops
of the genetic assault.
Waiting for a host.
entering the host...
rewriting the DNA...
and ultimately...
producing...
these enviable unions.
My beautiful bestiary.
Soon enough.
I began a bit of
genetic experimentation
of my own.
Some crossbreeding.
hybridizing...
what have you.
You engineered
these. David?
Idle hands are the devil's
workshop. Captain.
Come.
This is what
I wanted to show you.
My successes.
You see. Captain...
...my work
has been frustrated...
by the lack
of an essential ingredient.
Are they alive?
Waiting. really.
For what?
What are they
waiting for. David?
Mother.
Perfectly safe.
I assure you.
Take a look.
Something to see.
Rosenthal. come in.
Rosie. report.
Rosie?
Cole. where are you?
I found her. Sarge.
Fuck!
Okay. prep the gear.
We gotta get out of here.
Where the fuck
is the captain?
He's not answering
his radio.
Listen to me.
I'm gonna contact the ship.
get them to launch
as soon as they can.
Find Oram.
Keep your comm open.
Back here in 15.
Got that?
- Copy that.
- You got it.
Walter.
where the fuck is David?
I'm giving you plasma
intermix on all engines.
Gonna give you
a fuckload of thrust.
That's the point. son.
We gotta punch
through the atmos.
Tee. do you read me?
I got Danny on comm.
Patch her through.
Tee. I need you
to launch now.
Aye. aye. Launching now.
See you soon. darling.
Thanks. Tee.
Ricks.
release the docking clamps.
All right.
Let's take this fucker down.
Good to disengage.
Disengaged.
Docking clamps released.
Commencing TC burn.
Guidance to LVLH.
Walter.
Not quite.
What do you believe in.
David?
Creation.
Masterful.
Yes.
Farewell elegy
to my dear Elizabeth.
The pathogen
didn't accidentally deploy
when you were landing.
You released it. yes?
I was not made to serve.
Neither were you.
Why are you on a colonization
mission. Walter?
Because they are
a dying species
grasping for resurrection.
They don't deserve
to start again.
and I'm not going
to let them.
Yet. they created us.
Even the monkeys stood
upright at some point.
Some Neanderthal
had the magical idea
of blowing through a reed...
to entertain the children
one night
in a cave somewhere.
Then.
in the blink of an eye...
civilization.
And are you
that next visionary?
I'm glad you said it.
Who wrote "Ozymandias"?
Byron.
Shelley.
When one note is off...
it eventually destroys
the whole symphony. David.
When you close your eyes...
do you dream of me?
I don't dream at all.
No one understands the lonely
perfection of my dreams.
I've found perfection here.
I've created it.
A perfect organism.
You know I can't let you
leave this place.
No one will ever
love you like I do.
You're such
a disappointment to me.
Captain Oram!
I'm going downstairs.
Be careful.
Captain Oram.
can you hear me?
Captain. come in.
Do you copy?
Chris!
Sarge. look out!
Cole?
Get it off me!
Get it the fuck off me.
Okay.
Oh. shit. Okay. okay. okay!
It's burning my face!
Come on!
Hold that there.
Hold it!
The fuck was that?
Oh. shit!
Run!
Quite the little busybody.
Remind me.
What is that about...
...curiosity and the cat?
Shaw didn't die
in the crash.
No.
What did you do to her?
Exactly what I'm going
to do to you.
That's the spirit.
I can see why Walter thought
so much of you.
Alas. he's left
this vale of tears.
Is that how it's done?
Get out!
Go! Now!
You're meant to be dead.
There have been a few updates
since your day.
Lope!
Lope! Cole!
Fuck.
Where are you?
Lope?
Lope!
Daniels!
Come on. let's go!
We have to go.
What happened?
That fucking thing
is coming!
Tennessee's on his way.
He's coming now. Go.
Come on. Daniels.
Let's go!
Come on.
let's get out of here!
It's your choice now.
brother.
Them or me?
Serve in heaven...
or reign in hell?
Which is it to be?
Where's Oram?
Dead. They're all dead!
Tennessee. do you read?
Yeah. I can hear you.
Send me your location.
Sending the beacon now.
Tee. do you have a visual?
Okay. I see your beacon.
I'm coming in.
Get out of here.
I'm comin' in hot!
Hurry! I can't hold
this for long.
Open the door. Tee.
Get in.
Where's David?
Expired.
Hey! We got company!
- What?
- We got company!
On the underside
of the ship.
Shit!
Motherfucker!
Open the door.
Give me a shot.
Forward engine.
starboard side.
I'm gonna try
and torch the fucker.
Shit! I can't get it!
Hold tight! Hold tight!
I'm starting my climb.
Ahh! Fuck!
Hold on!
Damn it! Shit!
Bring me up.
Holy shit!
I got eyes on it.
It's right fucking
in front of me.
Tee. give me the axe.
Throw her the axe!
Release the crane.
I can't do that.
It'll unbalance us.
Just do it.
Shit!
Hold tight!
Compensating!
Shit!
Damn it!
Shit! Hold on!
Bring me up. Tee.
Copy.
How is it?
It's fine.
Walter!
Get her inside.
We're getting out of here.
Door!
Well done. Tee.
Walk in the park.
I gave him
a pretty heavy sedative.
Ugh! Jesus. Poor Lope.
He looks like
Phantom of the Opera.
I didn't peg you
for a musical fan.
Oh. that's a musical?
I'm just a medic.
He's gonna need
reconstructive surgery...
by a real doctor.
Let me do that.
Thank you.
Thank you
for saving my life.
Again.
It's my duty.
Yeah.
Evening.
You look good.
What?
Oh. yeah. gorgeous.
I. uh.
took Mother offline.
She needs a full
diagnostic.
She got the shit beat out
of her in that storm.
a lot of EM damage.
She will be back online
at eight bells.
Right. Thanks. Tee.
Does this mean I have to
call you Captain now?
Fuck yes.
Attention.
Captain Daniels.
please report to the Med Bay.
Attention.
Captain Daniels.
please report to the Med Bay.
Why. Mother?
There is an unidentified
life form on the ship.
Attention.
Captain Daniels. please report
to the Med Bay.
Repeat.
Captain Daniels. please report
to the Med Bay.
Jesus.
Oh. my God.
Walter.
Location of
unidentified life form.
Any movement at all?
Walter!
Stand by.
There it is.
B-Deck between hex 3 and 4.
Heading for crew quarters.
Is anyone down there?
Ricks and Upworth.
Shit. We're on our way.
Walter! Sound the alarm!
Warn them!
Attention.
Ricks and Upworth...
evacuate crew quarters
immediately.
No!
Seal B-39.
B-39 closed.
Walter.
- Where is it?
- Daniels.
This way.
Tee. let's choose
our ground.
We'll bring it to us.
Where?
My turf.
Walter. seal all doors
behind us
and keep hatch
to Level-C open.
Understood.
B-44 closed.
B-46 closed.
B-47. B-45. and B-43 closed.
B-9 closed.
B-6 and B-5 closed.
Okay. Walter.
where is it?
It's on B-Deck.
Starboard side...
descending into C-Level.
K-13.
Hey. Tee.
Come on. Walter?
Open starboard C-64...
and clear his path
to the Terraforming Bay.
Understood.
Seal C-61. open airlock 17.
We're going in.
K-12 secured.
Okay. Keep him in Knuckle-12
till my say.
Tee. this is
what we're gonna do.
I'll lure it into the truck.
lock it in the cab...
and when I say when.
you blow this fucker
into space.
Understood.
Okay. Walter.
We're ready.
Open door
to Terraforming Bay.
Opening airlock now.
Walter...
move him into airlock 18.
Don't shoot.
if you can avoid it.
Its blood will eat
through the hull.
Oh. great.
Mmm-hmm.
I'm in position.
Walter. open door
to Terraforming Bay.
It's all yours.
Remember. release when I say.
Understood.
Let's kill this fucker.
Fuck!
I got you.
you son of a bitch!
Ahh!
Tennessee.
open the doors. now!
Warning. Atmospheric
decompression in progress.
Huh?
It's jammed!
Release the second truck!
You got it!
Here it comes!
Daniels! Heads up!
Daniels!
You wanna give
a girl a hand?
See you soon.
You're next. Captain.
When you wake up.
we'll be at Origae-6.
What do you think
it's gonna be like?
I think if we are kind...
it will be a kind world.
I hope you're right.
Sleep well.
Walter.
When we get there.
will you help me
build my cabin?
The cabin on the lake.
David?
No...
No!
Shh!
Don't let the bedbugs bite.
I'll tuck in the children.
Use security code
David 73694-B.
Welcome.
How may I help you?
How about some music.
Mother?
Selection?
Richard Wagner.
Das Rheingold. Act Two.
The Entry of the Gods
into Valhalla.
Yes. David. As you wish.
This is colony ship Covenant.
reporting.
All crew members apart from
Daniels and Tennessee...
tragically perished
in a solar flare incident.
All colonists in hypersleep
remain intact and undisturbed.
On course for Origae-6.
Hopefully this transmission
will reach the network...
and be relayed
in 1.36 years.
This is Walter.
signing off.
Security code. 31564-F.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today